<mediawiki lang="en" version="0.3" schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.3/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.3.xsd" xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.3/">
  <siteinfo>
    <sitename>Staff Wiki</sitename>
    <base>http://www.wikia.com
    <generator>MediaWiki 1.7alpha</generator>
    <case>first-letter</case>
      <namespaces>
      <namespace key="-2">Media</namespace>
      <namespace key="-1">Special</namespace>
      <namespace key="0"></namespace>
      <namespace key="1">Talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="2">User</namespace>
      <namespace key="3">User talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="4">Staff Wiki</namespace>
      <namespace key="5">Staff Wiki talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="6">Image</namespace>
      <namespace key="7">Image talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="8">MediaWiki</namespace>
      <namespace key="9">MediaWiki talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="10">Template</namespace>
      <namespace key="11">Template talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="12">Help</namespace>
      <namespace key="13">Help talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="14">Category</namespace>
      <namespace key="15">Category talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="100">Portal</namespace>
      <namespace key="101">Portal talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="102">Blog</namespace>
    </namespaces>
  </siteinfo>
  <page>
    <title>SpamRegex</title>
    <id>1905</id>
    <revision>
      <id>5811</id>
      <timestamp>2006-12-12T09:49:55Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Sannse</username>
        <id>45</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Product Structure */</comment>
      <text space="preserve">&lt;H1&gt;Product
Requirements&lt;/H1&gt;
==Product Description==
: This special page is to provide a more convenient way of viewing,
adding and removing phrases blocked from editing. It's main concept is
to populate ''$wgSpamRegex'' before the actual check goes (which
disallows of saving a page when it contains any of given ''bad''
expressions).
==Product Assumptions==
* we use a shared database (so the block is enabled on multiple wikias)
* we use memcached (so database operations are sped up)
* user of this special page should belong to the 'staff' group
* we do not allow complex regular expressions to be entered (for now,
the script escapes regex special characters)
==Product Features==
:;Basic functionality
:: Ability to add, view and remove expressions, and see who put them
there and when.
==Key Product Concepts==
:;Data fetched from shared database
:: Data should be fetched from a shared database, supported with the
use of memcached instead of hardwritten from the file.
:;Submit form on one page with the list
:: Easier to manage than having them on two separated special pages.
==Product Unknowns==
: (coming up next)
==Potential Product Issues==
: When admin blocks an expression that is already contained on some
pages, the user editing them and trying to save will still be displayed
an error. Hopefully, it should be self-explanatory to the user. Also,
allowing complex regular expressions can generate php errors on editing
(for all users). &lt;strike&gt;The latter should be resolved by now by
escaping regex special characters.&lt;/strike&gt;
::Now, regular expressions are validated, and the use of special regex
characters is allowed.
==Product Interface==
: A special page. Allows to browse, add or remove expressions.
==Product Structure==
* '''Files'''
** '''SpamRegex.php''' ''contains includes for the files in the folder,
this one replaces old regexBlock.php
** '''/SpamRegex''' ''folder containg the core of the extension plus
docs''
*** '''README''' ''contains installation instructions and product
description''
*** '''SpamRegexCore.php''' ''contains the blocking utility and use of
the hook''
*** '''SpecialSpamRegex.php''' ''Special Page for viewing and managing
block list''
*** '' '''SimplifiedRegex.php''' - 'this one is required also by
[[RegexBlock]]'
* '''SQL''' CREATE TABLE `spam_regex` ( `spam_id` int(5) NOT NULL
auto_increment, `spam_text` varchar(255) NOT NULL, `spam_timestamp`
char(14) NOT NULL, `spam_user` varchar(255) NOT NULL, PRIMARY KEY
(`spam_id`), UNIQUE KEY `spam_text` (`spam_text`), KEY `spam_timestamp`
(`spam_timestamp`), KEY `spam_user` (`spam_user`) ) ;
* '''Installation'''
# Create the tables.
# Copy the '''/SpamRegex''' folder and its contents into /extensions.
# Copy '''SpamRegex.php''' to /extensions.
# If not already supplied with [[RegexBlock]] extension, copy
'''SimplifiedRegex.php''' into /extensions.
# Include the SpamRegex.php in GlobalSettings.php.
# This extension uses Memcached - please check if Memcached is
configured properly in Global/LocalSettings.
::That should do the trick. If people belonging to staff cannot access
the extension, check if relogin helps. If not, please check if the
staff permissions are not overwritten after the initialization of the
extension. If that is the case, the permissions should be rather
appended (the extension adds one new permission right).
==Product Use Cases==
# '''Blocking an unwanted expression'''
::An expression is found particularily nasty and therefore is banned
from editing.
::;Step 1 (An admin blocks that expression)'''
:::Admin inserts the username into the database via the special page
spamregex.
::;Step 2 (The user cannot save page containing that expression)
:::When any user tries to save any page containing that expression, the
page will not be saved and an explanation will be presented to the
user.
==Product Bugs==
:Please test it on http://fp006.qa.wikia.com/wiki/Special:Spamregex.
(it requires staff group rights).
:'''Known Bugs''':
: (coming up next)
==FEEDBACK==
Please post any comments or thoughts here.
* ''Will this special page be global and only exist on one wiki (the
central, or staff)? If so, it should probably be locked to (and
viewable by) only staff? If viewable by non-staff, bypassing it would
be much easier. [[User:Splarka|Splarka]] 00:53, 18 November 2006
(UTC)''
:: ''Right. I have made it that only staff members can view/use it.
Should work. And I will put up some regex validation there, now it
returns error on match when the expression is malformed.
--[[User:Bartek|Bartek]] 14:03, 21 November 2006 (UTC)''
*All looks good on this test -- [[User:Sannse|Sannse]] 11:07, 27 November 2006
(UTC)
*''I've allowed complex regular expressions to be entered, as Splarka
said, with a validator checking them before insertion. -
--[[User:Bartek|Bartek]] 16:01, 27 November 2006 (UTC)''
* Also, as Angela wrote today, the message should be edited and point
to a help page (to avoid confusion) - --[[User:Bartek|Bartek]] 08:32,
12 December 2006 (UTC)
[[Category:Features]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
