<mediawiki lang="en" version="0.3" schemaLocation="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.3/ http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.3.xsd" xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.mediawiki.org/xml/export-0.3/">
  <siteinfo>
    <sitename>Wikia</sitename>
    <base>http://www.wikia.com/wiki/Main_Page
    <generator>MediaWiki 1.7alpha</generator>
    <case>first-letter</case>
      <namespaces>
      <namespace key="-2">Media</namespace>
      <namespace key="-1">Special</namespace>
      <namespace key="0"></namespace>
      <namespace key="1">Talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="2">User</namespace>
      <namespace key="3">User talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="4">Staff Wiki</namespace>
      <namespace key="5">Staff Wiki talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="6">Image</namespace>
      <namespace key="7">Image talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="8">MediaWiki</namespace>
      <namespace key="9">MediaWiki talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="10">Template</namespace>
      <namespace key="11">Template talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="12">Help</namespace>
      <namespace key="13">Help talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="14">Category</namespace>
      <namespace key="15">Category talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="100">Portal</namespace>
      <namespace key="101">Portal talk</namespace>
      <namespace key="102">Blog</namespace>
    </namespaces>
  </siteinfo>
  <page>
    <title>RegexBlock</title>
    <id>1873</id>
    <revision>
      <id>6278</id>
      <timestamp>2006-12-29T20:42:46Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Sannse</username>
        <id>5</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>/* Help page */</comment>
      <text space="preserve">:&lt;small&gt;See
[[Cross wiki user blocks]] for a list of users blocked the old
way.&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;H1&gt;Product Requirements&lt;/H1&gt;
==Product Description==
: This is the automated version of the original regexBlock extension.
It takes data out of shared the database instead out of hardwritten
text inside of the file (''uses memcached to speed up the operations,
mostly on the side of checking edits'') and applies blocking to all
users, groupped by blocker's names. There is also a Special Page
(restricted to users with the preexisting 'block' ability) that allows
to block, view (also view by blockers) and unblock user names and IP
addresses. Current version also allows to block entire IP addresses (no
range or partial blockings in this case).
: Will also include in this one an ability to prevent new account
creation (yes, such a thing already exists in IP Blocks, but is not
multi-wikia-wide).
==Product Assumptions==
* we use a shared database (so the block is enabled on multiple wikias)
* we use memcached (so database operations are sped up)
* user of this special page should have the rights to block
* we take care of account creation prevention multi-wikia style right
here
==Product Features==
:;Basic functionality
:: Ability to block users by their names when they try to edit pages,
getting data out of the database, special page for managing blocks.
:;Extended functionality
:: Ability to block IP addresses, use of memcached, viewing blocks by
blockers.
:;Additional functionality
:: Ability to block new account creation on multiple wikias, displaying
efficiency statistics for particular blocks (who, when, from where
tried to edit and was blocked), allowing to set expiration period for
blocks (which is already done).
==Key Product Concepts==
:;Data fetched from shared database
:: Data should be fetched from a shared database, supported with the
use of memcached instead of hardwritten from the file.
:;Submit form on one page with the list
:: Easier to manage than having them on two separated special pages.
:;May be extended by having more statistics, timestamps, allow blocks
by IP ranges, and such
:: We can add some statistics into separate tables (like the reason -
rather an internal note for admin, why this particular user has been
blocked, or the IP's from which the user tried to login etc.).
==Product Unknowns==
* Should we have a similar page for usernames excluded from blocking
(when we block some IPs)? This could be linked to this project (the new
special page would fetch some data from this one).
* Include ability to block entire IP ranges? There are already
indications that it would be useful.
* Include timestamps? For now, the blocks are there for infinity.
** Timestamps are now included. Expired blocks are deleted
automatically when a blocked user tries to edit and an expired block is
then applied. In such case, the block is discarded and user can edit.
Admin can also remove expired blocks manually from list (they are
denoted 'EXPIRED' in red font)
* Show more information? Like for example statistics, which users tried
to login from which IPs and how many times, etc.
==Potential Product Issues==
* As we are able to block entire IP addresses, so there is more need
for a utility to allow specific users identified by their usernames to
edit anyway, even when they log from the blocked address. Similar
request already exists here:
[[Product_Priorities:_Ops_Upgrades_Bugs#General]]. The special page to
exclude blocks could integrate both IP Blocks and Regexblocks or it
could be just two separate special pages.
* &lt;strike&gt;The blocks are permanent at the moment. So there is
more attention required to them.&lt;/strike&gt;
: Which is untrue now. The blocks can be made with a chosen expiration
time. After that, then can be removed manually or on block. Either way,
they will be harmless.
* also a note: on older versions of MW when the user is regexblocked
(s)he cannot also create accounts (same goes for normal IP blocks), on
newer (I've tested it personally on 1.8.2) it allows a separate user
account creation block - it's about the
code, and since I was developing a clean extension, I didn't want to
alter the MW code itself. This leads to a situation, when the same
block of one vandal will allow him/her to create account on one wiki,
and disallow on the other (assuming that they will have different
versions and the option 'block account creation' will be unchecked).
==Product Interface==
: Has one Special Page named Regexblock. It displays a form, used for
adding blocks, and a list, used for managing blocks.
: The form has a field, specyfing user name or IP that we want to
block. While not required for a successful block, there are three more
options: whether match should be '''exact''', whether we should deny
this user '''account creation''', or the '''expiration period''', after
which the block will be invalid.
: The list can be filtered by usernames of the blockers. Each row
displays following information: ''username or IP address blocked'',
''username of the blocker'' and a ''link to unblock''. The unblock
requires no confirmation and is processed instantenuosly. The list can
be traversed as all standard lists in special pages (prev, next,
display by 20, 50 etc.). Each row also has the link to '''statistics'''
for a particular block.
==Product Structure==
* '''Files'''
** '''regexBlock.php''' ''contains includes for the files in the
folder, this one replaces old regexBlock.php
** '''/regexBlock''' ''folder containg the core of the extension plus
docs''
*** '''README''' ''contains installation instructions and product
description''
*** '''regexBlockCore.php''' ''contains the blocking utility and use of
the hook''
*** '''SpecialRegexBlock.php''' ''Special Page for viewing and managing
block list''
*** '''SpecialRegexBlockStats.php''' ''Special Page for displaying
stats for particular blocks''
*** '' '''SimplifiedRegex.php''' - this one is required also by
[[SpamRegex]] ''
* '''SQL''' CREATE TABLE `blockedby` ( `blckby_id` int(5) NOT NULL
auto_increment, `blckby_name` varchar(255) character set latin1 collate
latin1_bin NOT NULL, `blckby_blocker` varchar(255) character set latin1
collate latin1_bin NOT NULL, `blckby_timestamp` char(14) NOT NULL,
`blckby_expire` char(14) NOT NULL, `blckby_create` tinyint(1) NOT NULL
default '1', `blckby_exact` tinyint(1) NOT NULL default '0',
`blckby_reason` tinyblob NOT NULL, PRIMARY KEY (`blckby_id`), UNIQUE
KEY `blckby_name` (`blckby_name`), KEY `blckby_timestamp`
(`blckby_timestamp`), KEY `blckby_expire` (`blckby_expire`) ) ; CREATE
TABLE `stats_blockedby` ( `stats_id` int(8) NOT NULL auto_increment,
`stats_user` varchar(255) character set latin1 collate latin1_bin NOT
NULL, `stats_blocker` varchar(255) character set latin1 collate
latin1_bin NOT NULL, `stats_timestamp` char(14) NOT NULL, `stats_ip`
char(15) NOT NULL, `stats_match` varchar(255) character set latin1
collate latin1_bin NOT NULL default '-', `stats_wiki` varchar(255) NOT
NULL default '', PRIMARY KEY (`stats_id`), KEY `stats_timestamp`
(`stats_timestamp`) ) ;
* '''Installation'''
# Create tables in the shared database.
# Copy folder /regexBlock to /extensions, copy SimplifiedRegex.php to
/extensions ('''do not''' copy regexBlock.php yet!).
# Edit regexBlock.php and set '''REGEXBLOCK_PATH''' to its correct
value.
# Copy regexBlock.php to /extensions.
:That should do the trick. If people belonging to staff cannot access
the extension, check if relogin helps. If not, please check if the
staff permissions are not '''overwritten''' after the initialization of
the extension. If that is the case, the permissions should be rather
appended (the extension adds one new permission right).
==Product Use Cases==
# '''Blocking a vandalising user by a username'''
::A user is vandalising over different wikias. An admin blocks the user
by adding his/her username to the block list. The user cannot edit
pages anymore until the block is released.
::;Step 1 (An admin blocks user)'''
:::Admin inserts the username into the database via the special page
regexblock.
::;Step 2 (The user cannot edit pages)
:::Blocked user (a user that his/her username '''contains''' the
blocked username) tries to edit. There goes a block check, and there is
a match. Now, the expiration check is done. If the block is still
valid, unfortunate (vandalising) user will be displayed a message that
this particular user is blocked, along with the name of the blocker.
Also, on a successful block, an entry into the database is made.
::;Step 3 (Admin releases the block)
:::When the situation is under control, admin can ublock the user (or
not, if the user's actions made clear that the block should be
permanent). Admin can also view statistics for this particular block
(frequent attempts to edit despite being blocked may encourage admin to
make a more permanent block...).
# '''Blocking a vandalising user by an IP address'''
:: A user is vandalising over different wikias. An admin blocks the
user by adding his/her IP address to the block list. No users logging
from that IP will be able to edit the pages.
::;Step 1 (An admin blocks '''full''' IP address)
:::Admin inserts the '''full''' IP address into the database via the
special page regexblock (''a partial or range IP address will be
treated like a username. This is to avoid situations such as when a '3'
block blocks all IP's including '3'. Regular expressions.''). ::;Step 2
(The user cannot edit pages)
:::When a user logging in from a particular IP address (it has to be an
'''exact''' match) tries to edit, he/she will be displayed a message
that this particular user is blocked, along with the name of the
blocker. Also, all non-logged users from that IP address will be
blocked.
::;Step 3 (Admin releases the block)
:::When the situation is under control, admin can ublock this IP
address (or not, if the user's actions made clear that the block should
be permanent).
==Product Bugs==
:Please test it on http://fp006.qa.wikia.com/wiki/Special:Regexblock.
(it requires staff group rights). Account creation prevention mode may
not work properly at the moment - still working on that.
:'''Known Bugs''':
:* there is a little glitch when someone unblocks the last block by a
particular blocker (it shows 'All' on the select, but the list is
empty, the only exception is when unblocked row was the last on the
global list)
==Discussion==
[[User:Kaz3t]]: I'm not convinced that currently way for blocking user
by name is the best. For example user name can consist of his real name
and surname. So if we block user "John" we also block users "Johnny",
"John Smith", etc. In my opinion we should have choice - multi-block
(as it is now) and single-block (for example when we want to block this
and only this specified user we put his name between quotation-marks).
::: Yes, you got a point. Umm, but wouldn't a checkbox be better? It
would be more obvious on the first sight, I believe.
--[[User:Bartek|Bartek]] 16:03, 17 November 2006 (UTC)''
::: I added a checkbox just for that, should be working fine.
--[[User:Bartek|Bartek]] 16:01, 20 November 2006 (UTC)
* The message that a user sees is the same whether it is a similar name
block or a specific name block (or even an IP block). I think this
needs to either be made more general, or made variable. The reason set
is: "This username is prevented from editing due to vandalism by a user
with a similar name. Please create an alternate user name or contact
Wikia about the problem"
:::: There are four types of messages now (displayed to the blocked
user). First, is the reason specified by an admin. If there is none,
different messages will be displayed for: exact username match, IP
address match and a regex username match. - --[[User:Bartek|Bartek]]
13:07, 24 November 2006 (UTC)
* Is it possible to block ''just'' creation of accounts? for example to
stop future creation of sannse-like accounts while still allowing me to
edit? (this isn't vital though)
:::: Good point. For the moment, it is not possible with this
extension. It will be added in the future. - --[[User:Bartek|Bartek]]
09:42, 24 November 2006 (UTC)
* When it's an exact match block, this is mentioned on the listing.
Could it also be
mentioned when it is not exact? It would make this listing clearer. For
example:
** Bartek (exact match) (account creation block) (blocked by: Sannse)
on (etc.)
** Bartek (regex match) (account creation block) (blocked by: Sannse)
on (etc.)
:::: Changed already --[[User:Bartek|Bartek]] 09:34, 24 November 2006
(UTC)
*
http://fp006.qa.wikia.com/index.php?title=Special:Regexblockstats&amp;target=sannse
- I think all other logs have newes entries at the top. Can this one be
reversed?
:::: Done - --[[User:Bartek|Bartek]] 09:39, 24 November 2006 (UTC)
* I think that's all I can come up with, this is wonderful! thanks so
much for getting this going :) -- [[User:Sannse|Sannse]] 18:13, 23
November 2006 (UTC)
* The list of blocks is in alphabetical order. Is this the best way? I
think it may be, I'm just used to seeing such things in time order.
:::: Right. For the time being, it is in a descending time order. Feel
free to test and I will change to what will be best. -
--[[User:Bartek|Bartek]] 14:03, 27 November 2006 (UTC)
* Expired blocks are shown - useful? or are they quickly going to fill
up the blocklog?
:::: Now they are hidden. - --[[User:Bartek|Bartek]] 14:03, 27 November
2006 (UTC)
* All seems to work as advertised :) -- [[User:Sannse|Sannse]] 11:32,
27 November 2006 (UTC)
* A community team question. Do we want to change the default block
reasons at all? The current defaults are:
** "This IP address is prevented from editing due to vandalism" (IP
block)
** "This username is prevented from editing due to vandalism by a user
with a similar name. Please create an alternate user name or contact
Wikia about the problem" (RegEx block)
** "This username is prevented from editing due to vandalism" (Username
block)
:It won't always be vandalism. Is there something more general we can
use to cover vandalism, spamming, trolling, impersonation, etc?
[[User:Angela|Angela]] 10:53, 28 November 2006 (UTC)
:: how about "vandalism or other disruption" -- [[User:Sannse|Sannse]]
08:59, 30 November 2006 (UTC)
* as Splarka said earlier (05.12.2006) on IRC - ''an idea for blocking
IP ranges: a radio box: (*) whole username (exact match) ( ) regex
username ( ) IP or IP range in the first: "Splarka" would block just
that name... in the second "Spla" would block any username containing
that... and in the third: 75.72.55.78 would block just the user's IP,
and 75.72. could block 75.72.*.* simple summary: IP matching would be
made manual (easier to code probably?) although CIDR support might be
better than regex for IPs... eg 75.72.0.0/16''
* as Sannse and Splarka said today on IRC, it would be good to have an
option to block users in case-sensitive mode. One proposition is for an
exact match to be case-sensitive. - --[[User:Bartek|Bartek]] 09:06, 18
December 2006 (UTC)
:: As agreed, it will be case-sensitive for an exact match mode. -
--[[User:Bartek|Bartek]] 09:08, 18 December 2006 (UTC)
:::Which is already under testing
* and, as Emil said, it would be good to check if there is some proxy
check within the IP check (might be already implemented in existing
functions, since I am using class User's function to get the user's IP)
==Suggested messages==
* "This IP address is prevented from editing due to vandalism or other
disruption by you or by someone who shares your IP address. If you
believe this is in error, please [[Special:Contact|contact Wikia]]."
(IP block)
* "This username is prevented from editing due to vandalism or other
disruption by a user with a similar name. Please create an alternate
user name or [[Special:Contact|contact Wikia]] about the problem."
(RegEx block)
* "This username is prevented from editing due to vandalism or other
disruption. If you believe this is in error, please
[[Special:Contact|contact Wikia]]." (Username block)
==Help page==
[[Help:Global blocks]] (for contributors, not feature users)
==Post release==
A possible problem that's hard to confirm.
User:WatchTVEatDonutDrinkBeer complained of errors on trying to access
pages on wikiality. Their browser would direct them to
http://84.40.25.253/PageName
and they would get the 404 message: Not Found The requested URL
/Main_Page was not found on this server. Apache/2.2.0 (Unix)
mod_ssl/2.2.0 OpenSSL/0.9.7f PHP/5.1.4 Server at 84.40.25.253 Port 80
Because the timing of their last edit was so similar to a block Angela
had made: # wheels! (regex match) (account creation block) (blocked by:
Angela, generic reason) on 19:43, 29 December 2006 (unblock) permanent
block (stats)
I tried removing this block. Once I'd done that, he could access the
site normally. Replacing the block had no effect. I compared his IP
with the vandal's (User:Willy on wheels!) but they didn't match.
Perhaps a coincidence? But recording it here just in case it isn't --
[[User:Sannse|Sannse]] 20:42, 29 December 2006 (UTC)
[[Category:Features]]</text>
    </revision>
  </page>
</mediawiki>
