Rainbow Dash is a feisty Pegasus Pony she's a beautiful rainbow color tail and Mane
she's responsible for maintaining the weather in Ponyville
she is very loyal to her
friends one time she was offered a position among the
shadowbolts flying team but she said no and said deciding to stay and fly with her friends
Twilight Sparkle was so happy she
dubs Rainbow Dash the spirit of loyalty
she can be a very competitive Pony
sometimes she'll even cheat just so that she can win
once she lost a game of horseshoes to
Applejack and ask for a rematch because she doesn't like to lose
that's not being a very good
sport
Rainbow Dash loves to read
Twilight Sparkle gave her her first book while she was in the hospital
the Daring Do series quickly became one of rainbows
favorites
even though reading was for Eggheads she continue to read after she was released from the hospital
want to know more about Rainbow Dash
check out the My Little Pony wiki