buy now all viewers of Game of Thrones know the truth about Jon Snow's lineage
initially thought to be the
bastard son of Ned Stark it since been revealed that John is actually
aegon Targaryen
and as such as the rightful heir to the Iron Throne
it has been widely
believed that rhaegar
Targaryen
mad with lust is abducted lyanna Stark and steal her away in dorm
repeatedly
sexually assaulting her until she eventually
died in childbirth
even when the truth of Johnsburg was unveiled
friends dark you couldn't have known that in fact
rhaegar had an old is
previous marriage to Elia Martell
and legally married lyanna and
secret and the two was actually been in love
it took Samwell tarly's lover Gilly
absentmindedly
flipping through old
Scrolls in the Citadel to uncover this long hidden
truth
so Jon Snow is arguably the one person with the most
justifiable claim to the throne of the Seven Kingdoms
what is it a position he never expire too much less want he certainly take it if there are no other choice
but overall it's highly probable that Jon Snow would have no interest in being
King
and would likely see Power to someone more deserving of the throne
someone like Daenerys
Targaryen
perhaps
Jon Snow has never been portrayed as someone with any Lust For or even interest in power
believing himself to be a bastard all his life he would never have considered it to be something available to him to begin with
in
Westeros
bastards have no claim to their fathers land or title
in fact that's
typically
segregated from a
nobleman's true-born
children making the fact that Jon Snow was raised by net alongside the other star children a very rare thing
bastards in Westeros were usually happen to join the Nights Watch and indeed that seem to be with John believe was in store for him as well
when is Uncle benjen himself a swarm member of the Nights Watch
visited Winterfell in the first season
John
expresses interest in joining
it wasn't just waited in the slightest by Vengeance warning that there was a hard life
during this time at Castle black
Jon Snow more than acquitted
himself
earning the respect of both the Lord Commander jeor Mormont
as well as most of his brothers the one notable
exception being turn arms alliser Thorne
following Lord Commander Mormont
death
John was elected to be the new Lord Commander but you never seem completely comfortable in the role
after his betrayal in Murder By sworn Brothers he abandoned the Nights Watch
completely saying
I want you to
never been for an increase in
status power
or even for
legitimization from the status of
bastard
something Stannis Baratheon
offer Daymond John
refused
to
enforce
its first encounter in the night King has been only to ensure the survival of
humanity
even after being for Clayton King in the north by his Northern
Brethren.
Wednesday's veins
he's my king
from this day
until his
last day
eventually for claiming her to be his Queen
should the nurse discover the truth about his parentage there will no doubt be tension between them
but it's extremely
likely that John would be more than willing to see the power to her
after all he's already
Jon Snow is an honorable man
but he's never been portrayed as one of the last for power you may be the rightful heir to the iron throne
but in all likelihood
John would accept that roll only
grudgingly if it all
learn more about Jon Snow in Game of Thrones
wiki