Daenerys Targaryen
has all the makings of a great ruler
perhaps the greatest ruler
Westeros has ever seen
Danny has evolved from the meek timid girl she wants was into a beer sometimes
merciless it's still extremely
compassionate leader when she first appeared in the series her cruel and abusive
brother viserys
overshadowed and manipulated her
marrying her up to the leader of a Savage tribe of Dothraki
Warriors in order to secure an army but becerra's is rash
impulsive and
petulant Behavior ended when Danny's Dothraki
husband call Drogo gave him the crown he so desperately
wanted following both viserys and drogo's death
Daenerys is truly been through all manner of
struggles and managed to come out if not on top then at least
unbroken and
undefeated from being abandoned by drogo's khalasar to virtually dying of thirst and starvation in the red waste
to being betrayed by her trusted
bodyguard sir Jorah Mormont
break of day I'll have your head this morning to slaver's Bay
Barn weeds are being held captive by a rival tribe of Dothraki
daenerys's met all of these challenges and face them head-on is Steely resolve
tact and
intelligence
and she's done this while eating her own callus are comprised of freed slaves
unsullied Warriors and the few of drogo's khalasar that didn't abandon their Khaleesi
along with her three dragons and the Army she's amassed
Daenerys has proven herself to be a strong and capable
if
occasionally
violent and vengeful leader
she's rule not just her callus are but also the city-state of marine I will rule
she's masterfully managed to build alliances with Tyrion Lannister and Yara Greyjoy
and is set sail across the narrow sea to make her play for the Iron Throne
not only does Daenerys have a keen military mind she's also
incredibly
compassionate
the abuse she suffered at the hands of her brother has given her in men Sympathy for the downtrodden of the world and she has a
particularly
intense
distaste for those who
enslave
within a Shirley brutal struggle for control of Westeros looming it's anyone's guess who may ultimately
emerge Victorious
the given all the hardship she's faced the battle she's already won
and let's not forget
her three
dragons Daenerys Targaryen may be the safest bet and most worthy candidate to sit upon the iron throne